Guide to the Raisa Berg Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VI: Research and Reference Materials, 1919-2004
  - Subseries VI.1: Writings by Others, 1919-2003
    - Various authors:
      - Chedd, Grem, 1971 (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Cheney, J.: see White, Michael J.D.
      - Chernokozheva, I.S.: see Ushakov, B.P.
      - Chetverikov, Sergei S., 1919 1961 (with inscription) (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Chih-Ping Liu: see Nissani, Moti
      - Chovnik, Arthur: see Kidwell, Margaret G.
      - Christianson, J. Scott: see Stark, William S.
      - Chun-Fang Wu, 1980 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Chung Nan Chang, 1977 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Churchill, Frederick B., 1979 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Churikov, Nikolai A.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.
      - Clark, A. J.: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Clarke, B. C., 1979 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - Clavel, M. F.: see David, Jean
      - Clayton, F.E.: see Carson, Hampton L.
      - Clewell, Don B., 1979-1980 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - Cohen, Barry Mendel. Articles: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Cohen (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Cohen, M. M.: see Dudakov, E.
      - Cohet, Yves, 1971-1972 (see also: David, Jean) (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - Contreras, N.: see White, Michael J.D.
      - Cooper, David N.: see Krawczak, Michael
      - Corces, Victor G.: see Evgen'ev, Michael B.
      - Cordeiro, A. R.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Cotterman, C. W., 1953-1958 (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - Courtright, J.B.: see Cypher, J.J.
      - Cox, Nancy M.: see Lim, J.K.
      - Craig, Ronald A.: see Clewell, Don B.
      - Creed, E. R., undated (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - Cremer, Christoph: see Lohs-Schardin, Margit
      - Crow, James F., 1948-1977 (see also Kondrashov, Aleksei S.) (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Crozatier, Michele: see Bucheton, Alain
      - Crumpacker, David W., 1967 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Culbert, Timothy P.: see Lim, J.K.
      - Cullis, C. A., undated (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Culliton, Barbara J., 1982 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Cunha, Brito, da.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Cypher, J. J., 1982 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Daniel, Lajos, 1952-1957 (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Daniels, Stephen B.: see Kidwell, Margaret G.
      - David, Jean, 1961-1972 (Box 60, Folder 12 to 13)
      - Davies, R.B.: see Mertz, D.B.
      - Davidovskaia, A. E.: see Beliaev, D. K.
      - Dawson, Peter S., 1963-1966 (see also Sokoloff, Alexander) (Box 60, Folder 14)
      - Day, Alva: see Stebbins, G. Ledyard
      - De-Mao Chen: see Stark, William S.
      - Dean, Antony M., 1982-1985 (with author's inscription) (Box 60, Folder 15)
      - Delcour, J.: see Deltombe-Lietaert, M. C.; Elens, Antoine
      - DeLotto, Giovanni: see Brown, Spencer W.
      - Deltombe-Lietaert, M. C., 1978 (Box 60, Folder 15)
      - Demerec, Milislav, 1956-1966 (Box 60, Folder 16 to 17)
      - Demidova, Z. A.: see Dubinin, N. P.
      - Dempster, Everett R.: see Lerner, I. Michael
      - Dernoncourt-Sterpin, C.: see Elens, Antoine
      - Diehl, H.: see Anders, F.
      - Djordjevic, B.: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Dobrovol'skaia, Galina Nikolaevna: see Gershenzon, Sergei Mikhailovich
      - Dobzhansky, N.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, 1937-1973 (with author's inscription. See also Patterson, J.T.) (Box 61, Folder 1 to 8)
      - Dodson, Karen W.: see Berg, Douglas E.
      - Doll, Rhonda F.: see Lim, J.K.
      - Dover, Gabriel A., 1984 (with R.Berg's notes) (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Dowdeswell, W. H.: see Creed, E. R.
      - Dragavtsev, V. A., 1963 (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Drescher, W.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Dubinin, N. P., 1934-1961 (with author's inscription) (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Ducros, J.-F.: see Volobuev, V.T.
      - Dudakov, E., 1977 (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Duggleby, William F.: see Fox, Allen S.
      - Dunn, L. C., 1961-1965 (see also: Bennett, D.) (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - Dunny, Gary M.: see Clewell, Don B.
      - Dupre, John, 1987 (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - Dutrillaux, B.: see Volobuev, V.T.
      - Dykhuizen, Daniel E., 1983 with author's inscription (see also: Dean, Antony M.; Miller, Raymond D.) (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - Eden, Muray, 1967 (Box 62, Folder 3)
      - Edington, C.W.: see Lindsley, D.L.
      - Edmonds, Larry D.: see Khoury, Muin J.
      - Efroimson, V.P., 1957-1989 with author's inscription (see also in Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Efroimson: Box 4, Folders 5-17) (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Eggleston, William B.: see Engels, William R.
      - Egner, Carol: see Berg, Douglas E.
      - Ehrenfeld, Joan G.: see Ayala, F. J.
      - Ehrman, Lee, 1967-1968 (see also Petit, Claudine) (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - Elens, Antoine, 1957-1991 see Bertalanffy, V. L.; Deltombe-Lietaert, M. C. (Box 62, Folder 6)
      - Engelgardt, V.A.: see Frank, G.M.
      - Engels, William R., 1978-1993 (Box 62, Folder 7)
      - Enken, V.B., 1965 (Box 62, Folder 8)
      - Epling, Carl: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Epshtein, S.M.: see Regel', E.D.
      - Ermakov, I.P.: see Mosolov, Aleksandr Nikolaevich
      - Ermakova, T.V.: see Reperan, Zh.
      - Erokhina, I.D.: see Golubovskii, Mikhail
      - Espinel, A.: see Hoenigsberg, H.F.
      - Evgen'ev, Michael B., 1971 1992 (with author's inscription. See also Korochkin, L.I.) (Box 62, Folder 8)
      - Falls, Harold F.: see Cotterman C.W.
      - Fausto-Sterling, Anne: see Kidwell, Margaret G.
      - Feeley, Susan M.: see Kidwell, Margaret G.
      - Feldman, M.W.: see Sved, J.A.
      - Fialkov, D.N., 1961 (with author's inscription) (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Filatov, D.P., 1934-1937 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Filipchenko, Iu.A., 1919 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Fitzpatrick, Benjamin J.: see Sved, John A.
      - Flavell, Richard B.: see Dover, Gabriel A.
      - Fleuriet, A.: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Plus (Box 15, Folders 3-4)
      - Ford, Charles E., 1989 (with author's inscription) (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Ford, E. B.: see Creed, E. R.; Forman, Bruce
      - Forman, Bruce, undated (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Fortini, Mark E., 1993 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Fouillet, Pierre: see David, Jean
      - Fox, Allen S., 1971 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Frank, G.M., 1957 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Franklin, Ian R.: see Sokoloff, Alexander
      - Frazee, Joan E.: see Marquis, Robert J.
      - Freire-Maia, Ademar, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Frentzel-Beyme, R., undated (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Frese, K.: see Schwab, M.
      - Fresnaye, J.: see Boesiger, Ernest
      - Friesen, Heinrich, 1932 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Frisman, L.V.: see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Gaisinovich, A.E., 1965-1977 (Box 62, Folder 10)
      - Ganetzky, Barry: see Chun-Fang Wu
      - Garber, Richard L.: see Hafen, Ernst
      - Gartler, S.M.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Gegamian, G.V., 1980 (Box 62, Folder 11)
      - Gehring, Walter J.: see Hafen, Ernst; McGinnis, William
      - Gelbart, William M.: see Fox, Allen S.
      - Georgiev, Georgii P.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.
      - Georgiev, Pavel G.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.
      - Geptner, M. A.: see Dubinin, N. P.
      - Gerard, R.W., 1957 (Box 62, Folder 11)
      - Gerasimova, Tatiana I., 1981-1990 (with author's inscription) (Box 62, Folder 12)
      - Gerbil'skii, N.L., 1956 (with author's inscription) (Box 62, Folder 13)
      - Gerlach, J., 1941 (Box 62, Folder 13)
      - Gershenzon, Sergei Mikhailovich, 1941-1990 (with author's inscription. See also Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Gershenzon (Box 5, Folders 16-17) (Box 63, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Gibson, Campbell, 1960s (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Giliarov, M.S., 1942 (with author's inscription) (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Gilpin, Michael E.: see Ayala, F. J.
      - Ginzburg, E.Kh., 1973-1979 (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Glazunova, K.P., 1990 (with author's inscription) (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Glanville, E. V.: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Gliner, Erast B., undated (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Godovikova, V.A.: see Korochkin, L.I.
      - Gokhman, V.E.: see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Goldberg, Gregory I.: see Bowman, Lewis H.
      - Goldman, I.: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Goldman, William E.: see Bowman, Lewis H.
      - Goldovskii, A.M., 1957 (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Goldschmidt, Ernst: see Nielsen, Michael
      - Golubev, D.B.: see Smorodintsev, A.A.
      - Golubitsa, A. N.: see Beliaev, D. K.; Korochkin, L.I.
      - Golubovskii, Mikhail, 1966-2003 (with author's inscriptions. See also his articles in Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Golubovskii: Box 6, Folders 8-11) (Box 63, Folder 8 to 10)
      - Goodman, Morris, 1961 (Box 63, Folder 11)
      - Goriaeva, O.V.: see Mosolov, Aleksandr Nikolaevich
      - Graham, Loren R., 1977 (Box 63, Folder 11)
      - Granberg, Charles R., 1991 (with his note) (Box 63, Folder 11)
      - Green, Louis: see Miller, Raymond D.
      - Green, M.M., 1970-1980 (see also: Golubovskii, Mikhail; Slatko, Barton E) (Box 63, Folder 12)
      - Greenberg-Temin, Rayla, 1965 (Box 63, Folder 13)
      - Griswold, M. Scott, 1992 (Box 63, Folder 13)
      - Gromov, B.V.: see Osipov, D.V.
      - Gronau, Thomas: see Anders, Fritz
      - Grossarth-Maticek, R.: see Frentzel-Beyme, R.
      - Grossman, Abram (Alik). "The Genetic Basis for the Variability of Temperature sensitivity of ADH Alozymes in D. Melanogaster": see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Grosman, Alik (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Gudz'-Gorban', Aleksei Pavlovich: see Gershenzon, Sergei Mikhailovich
      - Gulyi, V.V., 1967 (Box 63, Folder 14)
      - Gumilev, Lev Nikolaevich, 1970-1971 (with author's inscription) (Box 63, Folder 14)
      - Gustapon, Thane, undated (Box 63, Folder 15)
      - Gutierrez, L.F.: see Hoenigsberg, H.F.
      - Gvozdev, V.A.: see Kaidanov, Leonid Z.
      - Hafen, Ernst, 1983 (Box 63, Folder 16)
      - Halle, E.S., von: see Lindsley, D.L.
      - Hardy, D. E.: see Carson, Hampton L.
      - Hartl, Daniel L., 1975 (see also: Dykhuizen, Daniel E., Dean, Antony M.; Miller, Raymond D.) (Box 63, Folder 16)
      - Hartman, Philip E.: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Hartman, Zlata: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Hartung, Nancy: see Hartl, Daniel L.
      - Hassenstein, Bernard, 1980 (Box 63, Folder 16)
      - Haute, J, van den: see Elens, Antoine
      - Hebert, Brenda M.: see Bowman, Lewis H.
      - Hedgecock, Dennis: see Ayala, F. J.
      - Hedrick, Philip W., 1979 (Box 63, Folder 17)
      - Heed, W. B.: see Carson, Hampton L.
      - Herrewege, Jeanine, van, 1971 (see also: David, Jean) (Box 63, Folder 17)
      - Herrmann, Jurgen, 1975-1977 (Box 63, Folder 17)
      - Hershey, Howard V.: see Taylor, Milton W.
      - Hill, Ronald S.: see Boyd, A. E.
      - Hinton, Claude W., undated (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Hirsch, Jerry, 1981 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Ho, Frank K.: see Sokoloff, Alexander
      - Hoenigsberg, H.F., 1982-1987 (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Holden, Larry: see Hedrick, Philip W.
      - Holland, George P, 1985 (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Hook, Ernest B., 1979 (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Howarth, Sheila: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Hoy, Marjorie A.: see Sokoloff, Alexander
      - Hubby, J.L.: see Lewontin, Richard C.
      - Huong Dang-Vu: see Tsubota, Stuart I.
      - Iablokov, A.V.: see Timofeev-Resovskii, Nikolai Vladimirovich
      - Iablokov-Khnzorian, S.M., 1968-1972 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Iakimenko, L.V.: see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Ianina, I.Iu.: see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Iatsenko-Khmelevskii, A.A., 1958 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Ibragimov, M., 1958 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Ignat'ev, M.V., 1944 (with author's inscription. See also Shapiro, N.I.) (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Ikeda, Hiroshi, 1973 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Il'in, Iurii V.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.; Kaidanov, Leonid Z.
      - Iltis, Wilfred Gregor, 1957-1965 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Ineich, I.: see Volobuev, V.T.
      - Inge-Vechtomov, S.G., 1979 (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Inouye, Nobuo, 1965 (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Iraizumi, Yuichiro: see Slatko, Barton E
      - Ischenko, V.G., 1967 (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Ishudsu, J.: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Iurchenko, N.N.: seeGolubovskii, M.D.
      - Ivannikov, A.V., undated (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Ivanov, Iu.N., 1970-1975 with author's inscription (see also Golubovskii, Mikhail; see also manuscript of his article: Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Ivanov, Iu.N.: Box 7, Folders 8-9) (Box 64, Folder 6)
      - Ivanov, Vladimir I.. Article, review, open letter: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Ivanov, Vladimir I. (Box 7, Folder 11) (Box 64, Folder 6)
      - Ivanov, Vladimir Nikolaevich, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 6)
      - Ivanova-Berg, M.M., 1962 (Box 64, Folder 6)
      - Ivanovskii, A.B.: see Korochkin, L.I.
      - Jaenel-Dess, G.: see Anders, F.
      - Jakubicek, Milan, 1970 (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - Jamblinne, A.Th, de: see Elens, Antoine
      - Jenkins, J.A.: see Mackinney, G.
      - Jensen, O. A.: see Bech, K.
      - Johnson, George R., 1965 (see also Sokoloff, Alexander) (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - Johnson, Terrell K.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.
      - Johnson-Schlitz, Dena M.: see Engels, William R.; Lim, J.K.
      - Johnstone, Rufus A., 2001 (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - Jousset, Francoise-Xaviere: see Thomas-Orillard, Michele
      - Kagan, Viktor Kusielevich: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Kagan, V.K. (Box 8, Folders 2-3)
        - "Dva obrashchentsa", (originally published in Kontinent)
        - "Estimation of Visual Task Complexity" (typescript)
        - "Vospominaniia o N.V.Timofeeve-Resovskom"
      - Kaidanov, Leonid Z., 1965-1991 (with author's inscription. See also Golubovskii, Mikhail; Karakin, E.I.) (Box 64, Folder 8)
      - Kalinin, O.M., 1972 (with author's inscription) (Box 64, Folder 9)
      - Kanaev, I.I., 1961-1971 (with author's inscription) (Box 64, Folder 9)
      - Kaneshiro, K. Y.: see Carson, Hampton L., Dobzhansky, T.
      - Kaplan, W.D., 1973-1974 (Box 64, Folder 9)
      - Kaplin, V.S.: see Korochkin, L.I.
      - Karaev, Kara: see Evgen'ev, Michael B.
      - Karakin, E.I., 1975-1989 (with author's inscription) (Box 64, Folder 10)
      - Karasik, G.I.: see Korochkin, L.I.
      - Kartavtsev, Iu.F.: see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Kaufman, Berwind P., 1963 (Box 64, Folder 11)
      - Kelman Iddles, Marcia: see Kaufman, Berwind
      - Kenigfest, N.B.: see Reperan, Zh.
      - Kenzior, Alexander L.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.
      - Kerkis, Iu.Ia., 1932 (see also Dubinin, N. P.) (Box 64, Folder 11)
      - Kernaghan, R.Peter: see Ehrman, Lee
      - Khokhutkin, I.M., 1971 (with author's inscription) (Box 64, Folder 12)
      - Kholodnyi, N.G., 1942 (Box 64, Folder 12)
      - Khoury, Muin J., 1991 (Box 64, Folder 12)
      - Khovanov, G.M., undated (Box 64, Folder 12)
      - Kidwell, James F., 1973-1976 (Box 64, Folder 13 to 14)
      - Kidwell, Margaret G., 1973-1993 (see also Bingham, Paul M.) (Box 64, Folder 13 to 14)
      - Kiknadze, I.I.: see Karakin, E.I.; Korochkin, L.I.
      - Kirpichnikova, E., 1992 (Box 64, Folder 15)
      - Kiselev, Sergei L.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.
      - Kiseleva, N.S., undated (Box 64, Folder 15)
      - Kiyasu, Phillip K.: see Kidwell, Margaret G.
      - Koch, P., 1975 (with author's inscription) (Box 64, Folder 15)
      - Kok, Irina Pavlovna: see Gershenzon, Sergei Mikhailovich
      - Kokoza, V.A.: see Karakin, E.I.
      - Kolchinskii, E.I.: see Lapo, A.V.
      - Kollinger, G.: see Schwab, M.
      - Kolosova, L.D., 1973 (see also Vorontsov, N.N.) (Box 64, Folder 15)
      - Kondrashov, Aleksei S., 1982-2002 (with author's inscription) (Box 65, Folder 1)
      - Korablev, V.P.: see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Kornilova, I.Iu.: see Mosolov, Aleksandr Nikolaevich
      - Korochkin, L. I., 1968-1985 (with author's inscription. See also Beliaev, D. K., Bogomolova, V.I., Karakin, E.I.) (Box 65, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Korochkina, L. S.: see Beliaev, D. K.; Karakin, E.I.
      - Korsakova, G.F.: see Svetlov, P.G.
      - Kosareva, A.A.: see Reperan, Zh.
      - Kral, Bohumil, 1974 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Krawczak, Michael, 199[?] (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Krotkova, A. P.: see Dubinin, N. P.
      - Krushinskii, L.V., 1945 (with author's inscription) (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Kuhn, Claudia, 1978 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Kuksinskaia, I.S.: see Kaidanov, Leonid Z.
      - Kulikova, V.G.: see Luchnik, N.V.
      - Kumaran, A. K.: see Cypher, J. J.
      - Kurbatova, O. L.: see Altukhov, IU. P.
      - Kuzin, B.A.: see Korochkin, L.I.
      - Lahr, E. L.: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Labeyrie, Vincent, 1968 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - Lakhanpal, Raj K.: see Sokoloff, Alexander
      - Lamy, Rowena, 1947 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - Lande, Russel, 1976-1979 (with author's inscription) (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - Lange, Kenneth: see Peltonen, Leena
      - Lange, Peter: see Sperlich, Diether
      - Langley, Charles: see Slatko, Barton E
      - Lankenau, Dirk-Henner: see Evgen'ev, Michael B.
      - Lankinen, P.: see Pinsker, W.
      - Lapo, A.V., 1988-2002 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Latter, B.D.H.: see Sved, John A.
      - Laven, Hannes, undated (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - Lavie, P.: see Boesiger, Ernest
      - Lavige, Jean-Marc, 1982 (see also Picard, Georges) (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - Layzer, David, 1978-1980 (with author's inscription) (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Lebedeva, L. I.: see Dubinin, N. P.
      - Lecher, Pierre: see Lavige, Jean-Marc
      - Lechien, J.: see Elens, Antoine
      - Lecompte, E.: see Volobuev, V.T.
      - Lefevre, G., Jr.: see Green, M.M.
      - Lenelle-Monfort, N.: see Deltombe-Lietaert, M. C.
      - Lepper, K.: see Ahuja, M.R.
      - Lerner, I. Michael, 1962-1965 (see also Dawson, Peter S.; Inouye, Nobuo; Sokoloff, Alexander) (Box 65, Folder 9)
      - Lerner, T.Ia.: see Karakin, E.I.
      - Leslie, Donald: see Needham, Joseph
      - Levan, Albert: see Nichols, Warren W.
      - Levene, Howard, 1945 1959 (see also Dobzhansky, Theodosius; Dunn, L.C.; Sokoloff, Alexander) (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Levin, V.L., 1970 (with author's inscription) (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Levine, Louis: see Dunn, L. C.
      - Levine, Michael: see Hafen, Ernst
      - Levinton, Jeffrey S., undated (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Levit, Georg S., 2005 (see also "Nomogenese: Evolutionstheorie jenseits von Darwinismus und Lamarckismus" in Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Levit, G.: Box 10, Folder 14) (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Levitan, N.B.: see Mosolov, Aleksandr Nikolaevich
      - Lewis, E.B., 1978 (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Lewontin, Richard C., 1966-1980 (see also Prakash, Satya) (Box 65, Folder 11)
      - Li, Wen-Hsiung, 1977 1982 (Box 65, Folder 12)
      - Liapunov, A.A., 1965-1974 (Box 65, Folder 13)
      - Liapunova, E.A., 1983-1987 (see also Kral, Bohumil, Vorontsov, N.N.) (Box 65, Folder 13)
      - Lichtenberger, M.: see Elens, Antoine
      - Lim, J.K., 1968-1992 (with author's inscription) (Box 65, Folder 14 to 15)
      - Limanskii, V. V.: see Altukhov, IU. P.
      - Lindsley, D.L., 1960 (Box 65, Folder 16)
      - Liu, C.P.: see Lim, J.K.
      - Liubishchev, A.A., 1962-1971 (with author's inscription. See also typescript of his papers "Poniatie nomogenez" presented at the conference in 1927 in Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Liubishchev: Box 11, Folder 2) (Box 65, Folder 17)
      - Lobashev, M.E., 1938 1970 (see also Kaidanov, Leonid Z.) (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Lodge, Jennifer K.: see Berg, Douglas E.
      - Lohs-Schardin, Margit, 1975-1979 (with author's inscription) (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Lowe, John B.: see Berg, Douglas E.
      - Lowry, Dorothy C., 1959 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Lubs, H.A., 1970 (with R.Lande note) (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Lucchesi, John C., 1978 (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Luchnik, N.V., 1956 (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Luchnikova, E.M.: see Lobashev, M.E.
      - Lukashina, N.S.: see Korochkin, L.I.
      - Luke, Wolfgang: see Anders, Fritz
      - Lukin, Ie.I., 1935 (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Lusis, Ia.Ia., 1971 (with author's inscription) (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Luyten, Norbert M.: see Bertalanffy, L.
      - Luke, W.: see Anders, F.
      - McClelland, G.A.H.: see Iltis, W.G.
      - McGinnis, William, 1983 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - McKenzie, Howard L., 1962 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - McKinney, H.H.: see Sprague, G.F.
      - McWhriter, K. G.: see Creed, E. R.; Forman, Bruce
      - Mack, Cornelia: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Mackay, Trudy F.C., 1984 (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - Mackey, Diane: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Mackinney, G., 1956 (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - Magrzhikovskaya, K.V., 1941 (see also Sakharov, V.V.) (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - Mahler, Brigitte: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Maksimovskii, L. F.: see Beliaev, D. K.; Korochkin, L.I.
      - Maletskii, Stanislav Ignat'evich, 1967-1991 (with author's inscription) (Box 66, Folder 5)
      - Malinovskii, A.A., 1941-1972 (with author's inscription) (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - Malogolowkin, Chana, 1957 1961 (see also Dobzhansky, Theodosius (Box 66, Folder 7)
      - Malotkov, Georgii, 1985 (Box 66, Folder 7)
      - Maluta, S. S.: see Alexandrov, Ui. N.; Gershenzon, Sergei Mikhailovich
      - Mamkaeva, K.A.: see Osipov, D.V.
      - Mampell, Klaus, 1946 (Box 66, Folder 7)
      - Manevich, E.D., 1945-1947 (with author's inscription) (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - Marikovskii, P.I., 1947 (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Marinkovic, Dragoslav, 1968 (see also Crumpacker, David W.) (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Marquis, Robert J., 1994 (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Martin, Diana W.: see Slatko, Barton E
      - Martin, M. Louise: see Khoury, Muin J.
      - Maruyama, Takeo, 1980 (see also Frank, G.M.) (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Mather, Wharton B.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Matjunina, Liliya V.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.
      - Matveeva, N.M.: see Korochkin, L.I.
      - Mayr, Ernst: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Matsunaga, Ei, 1981 (with author's inscription) (Box 66, Folder 10)
      - Matthews, Kathleen A.: see Slatko, Barton E
      - Matvienko, V.S., 1971 (Box 66, Folder 10)
      - Mazing, V.V., 1970-1971 (with author's inscription) (Box 66, Folder 11)
      - Mazing, R.A., 1939-1946 (with author's inscription) (Box 66, Folder 11)
      - Mechler, Bernard M., 1989 (see also McGinnis, William) (Box 66, Folder 12)
      - Medawar, P.B., 1955 (Box 66, Folder 12)
      - Medioni, Jean, 1977 (Box 66, Folder 12)
      - Medvedev, N.N., 1967 (Box 66, Folder 13)
      - Medvedev, Zhores, 1967 1981 (with author's inscription. See also articles and essays (typescript and clippings) in Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Medvedev, Zhores: Box 13, Folders 1-6) (Box 66, Folder 13)
      - Meister, G.K., 1921 (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Meister, Kay: see Levit, Georg S.
      - Meksina, N.S.: see Kaidanov, Leonid Z.
      - Meladze, 1943 (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Meller, G.I., undated (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Mendel, Gregor, 1866 (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Merle, Josselyne, 1968 (see also David, Jean) (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Mertz, D.B., 1968 (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Miatlev, V.D.: see Glazunova, K.P.
      - Michaelidis, Apostolos: see Sperlich, Diether
      - Mikhailov, D.1982 (Box 66, Folder 15)
      - Miller, Raymond D., 1988 (Box 66, Folder 15)
      - Mina, Mikhail V.: see Kondrashov, Aleksei S.
      - Minamori, Sumio, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 15)